[Music]
so
when i was a child we lived in a house
that stayed quite cold in winter
on frozen nights we'd put our sleeping
bags by our wood stove
and my father would read to us
[Music]
we had purchased two baby goats a few
weeks before
and unfortunately due to a congenital
issue one of them had passed away
the other was very sad and afraid of
being alone and so until we were able to
get him some new friends
he would spend the evening with us on
our sleeping bag wrapped in towels
i have a distinct memory of watching the
baby goat ears pricked
listening in on the storytelling as if
he could completely understand
it will always be one of my favorite
memories from my childhood
[Music]
so
my father was sometimes deployed in the
military and gone for a year at a time
so when we all sat together listening to
the sound of his voice over the
crackling flames
everything felt right and safe
even now i like to spend chilly evenings
wrapped up in a blanket with a good book
next to my furnace putting away my phone
and taking time to clear my mind of
racing thoughts
and worries
[Music]
my father's favorite books to read were
about myths and legends of ancient
peoples
one of my favorites was a children's
encyclopedia of greek mythology
a story that came to mind the other day
as i was collecting lilacs
was one about a beautiful wood nymph
named sedinja
she spent her days running through the
meadows and dancing with the wild
rabbits and fawns
one day the spirit pan saw her and was
jealous of her happiness
wanting it for his own so he decided to
steal her away from the hills and
mountains
but sadinja was a fairy's child and
afraid of pan's wily waves
so she turned herself into a lilac bush
and eluded him
now every time the lilac blooms the
sweet scent of the nectar is siddinja's
loving offering to the insects
and animals
[Music]
[Applause]
and
[Music]
so
wishing you a lovely day or night
full of dreams and stories and other
wonderful whimsical thoughts
sending my love
today i was in an experimental mood
and i decided to try reinventing one of
my favorite
puerto rican desserts and the dessert
that i was
taking inspiration from is called arroz
condulce
since i love arroz conduce i decided to
instead of use raisins to replace them
with lilac flowers
and in retrospect i think i would have
just infused the milk with lilac
and just made it without the blooms
themselves in the mix
but it was still really good so i really
really liked it and i'll leave
both recipes below and so you can take a
look at them
they're just wonderful i highly
recommend both
and thank you to everyone who has
reached out wondering how i'm doing now
that i'm working more from home
and i would say that it's been really
nice but i do miss my students
so i'm very excited to visit them and
hopefully get a little kinder group
together to do some art classes in the
future
um it's it's a very exciting idea to me
so i hope that will happen soon but yes
i am
really enjoying it it's kind of an
interesting new phase of my life that
has been taking a little bit of
adjustment but
it's nice to spend more time at home as
well
but it can be a challenge too so i'm
learning as i go